<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Herbalist Background</name>
		<description>Background for a character interested in herbs and herbal remedies</description>
		<update version="0.0.7">
			<file name="herbalist-background.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/novalore/aurora/master/user-novalore/backgrounds/herbalist-background.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Herbalist" type="Background" source="homebrew" id="ID_NOVALORE_BACKGROUND_HERBALIST">
		<description>
			<p>Picking herbs from a backyard garden, a hot house, or a forest outside of town the herbalist collects natural items that aid and harm. An herbalist can heal, poison, invigorate. They know the powers of plants and fungi to change how humanoids and beasts experience the world. They learn Druidic language even if they shouldn't be allowed.</p>
			<ul>
				<li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong> Nature, Survival</li>
				<li><strong>Tool Proficiencies:</strong> Herbalism kit</li>
				<li><strong>Languages:</strong> Druidic </li>
				<li><strong>Equipment:</strong> Sickle (obsidian if the character is not allowed to usse metal), 2 candles, Scroll case with 5 pieces parchment or a notebook, common clothes, component pouch, herbalist kit, 2 vials (1 with either antitoxin or healing potion).</li>
			</ul>
			<div element="ID_NOVALORE_BACKGROUND_HERBALIST_FEATURE_A_DASH" />
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="short">Nature, Survival, Herbalism Kit</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_NATURE" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SURVIVAL" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_MEDICINE" optional="true"/>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_HERBALISM_KIT" />
			<grant type="Language" name="Language (Herbalist)" id="ID_LANGUAGE_DRUIDIC"/>
			<grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_NOVALORE_BACKGROUND_HERBALIST_FEATURE_A_DASH" />
			<select name="Personal history" type="List">
				<item id="1">I saved people during a famine/draught.</item>
				<item id="2">I offered refuge to wounded animals.</item>
				<item id="3">A celestial, fey, or similar creature gave me knwoledge on rare herbs.</item>
				<item id="4">I was the only one in my village/community to listen to women and help them with health issues.</item>
				<item id="5">I could not formally study, but I learnt from an older herbalist.</item>
			</select>
			<select name="Ideal" type="List">
				<item id="1">I like animals and plants more than people. I'm always ready to poison someone to protect nature.</item>
				<item id="2">I don't like starting fights, I always think twice before attacking anybody.</item>
				<item id="3">I never underestimate others, all people have hidden talents.</item>
				<item id="4">People are just another type of animal, that's why I don't consider myself superior to other animals.</item>
				<item id="5">I always listen to opinions of others, even if they don't know what they're talking about.</item>
				<item id="6">I believe that every wound should be tended to, even if it's an enemy.</item>
				<item id="7">I consider the laws of nature the only real authority.</item>
			</select>
			<select name="Bond" type="List">
				<item id="1">Tribe is everything to me.</item>
				<item id="2">My family made me into who i am today, i will always be thankful to them.</item>
				<item id="3">I consider my sisters/brothers herbalists my only family.</item>
				<item id="4">I lost everybody who I cared about... now I'm trying to find anybody who will care about me.</item>
				<item id="5">I'm looking for new faces and stories, everybody have something to tell.</item>
				<item id="6">I want everyone to know my name and for my legacy to live on even hundred years later.</item>
			</select>
			<select name="Flaw" type="List">
				<item id="1">I think bad omens can predict future, I always believe them.</item>
				<item id="2">I'm the worst at navigation, if people say "go right", I will go left.</item>
				<item id="3">I sleep like a dead man, nothing can wake me up... sometimes I think even getting stabbed will not awake me.</item>
				<item id="4">I easily distract and lose focus on the mission.</item>
				<item id="5">I don't care about other people's feelings, it's their problem not mine.</item>
				<item id="6">I have seen too many injustices, I have a hard time trusting people. </item>
			</select>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Feature: A Dash of This, a Dollop of That" type="Background Feature" source="homebrew" id="ID_NOVALORE_BACKGROUND_HERBALIST_FEATURE_A_DASH">
		<supports>Background Feature</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Once per long rest you can find the various fungi, plants, and natural ingredients needed to make a concoction that can be employed as antitoxin, lesser cure, weak poison, tranquilizer or energizer.</p>
			<p>The resulting poultice has a shelf life of only 8h unless bottled, if bottled it stays effective for maximum 48h.</p>
			<ul>
				<li><strong>Antitoxin:</strong>A creature that ingests the poultice gains advantage on saving throws against poison for 1 hour.</li>
				<li><strong>Lesser healing: if applied on a wound it stops bleeding and the character recovers 1 HP immediately; if ingested the character will recover maximum from the next hit die rolled within 1 minute.</strong></li>
				<li><strong>Weak poison:</strong>A creature that touches or ingests the poultice must make a DC 10 Constitution saving throw or take 1d4 poison damage. On each successive failed save, the character takes 1 poison damage. After 1 successful save, the poison effect ends. This poison can be applied on weapons, the effect of the poison apply to targets hit with the weapon in the following ten rounds.</li>
				<li><strong>Tranquilizer:</strong>A creature that ingests the poultice or is hit with a weapon tainted with it must make a DC 10 Constitution saving throw or suffer a -1 Dexterity point for 10 rounds, if the saving throw is failed by 5 or more, the creature will also have disadvantage on Constitution and Dexterity saving throws for 10 rounds.</li>
				<li><strong>Energizer:</strong>Reduces one level of exhaustion for 1 hour.</li>
			</ul>
			</description>
		<sheet alt="A Dash of This, a Dollop of That">
			<description usage="1/Long Rest">You can find the various fungi, plants, and natural ingredients needed to make a concoction that can be employed as antitoxin, lesser cure, weak poison, tranquilizer or energizer. The resulting poultice has a shelf life of only 8h unless bottled, if bottled it stays effective for maximum 48h.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
</elements>
